hmm that is one of the principle and
that's actually a major principle
because the more you learn and here's a
problem a lot of us you know if you
don't have pictures hanging in memories
Hall you're not gonna be able to make
these connections all right and that's
why one of the first things you really
want to do is learn how to just hang
these pictures in your Hall right lock
them in your mind because you may not
you know even understand what the
picture is about right now but put it
there because something's gonna happen
one day one day you're going to be
minding your own business washing dishes
or and all of a sudden a picture is
gonna come to your mind and you gotta
like wait a minute wait a minute that
picture adds to that picture matches
this picture one of my favorite pictures
and I had this picture hanging in my
Hall for a long time and I was just like
I would always be like that's a messed
up story his story of David and
Bathsheba in this story of David and
Bathsheba David you know has Bathsheba's
husband killed
why because Bathsheba is pregnant and so
Bathsheba is pregnant with David's child
has he has her husband killed so that he
covers it up and then the Prophet Nathan
comes to him and you know gives me this
whole parable and then tells him you are
the man in this parable basically
exposing David I know what you've done
right David repents
he's totally sorry and Nathan says you
will live and you know praise God like
this is the power of repentance right
mm-hmm David repents and God tells
Nathan to tell David you're gonna leave
but the child that Bathsheba was
pregnant with is gonna die and I've
always thought to myself messed up story
messed up story like why how why would
that be right so I had that picture
hanging in memories Hall for a long time
and then one day I don't know what or
how but I was like wait a minute
that child doesn't have a name we don't
know who the child is the only thing we
know about that child was that it was a
male so this would have been the son of
David hmm so the son of David was
brought into this world because of
somebody else's sin and though he had
done no wrong died while David got to
live Wow all of a sudden I'm like whoa
you mean that little boy who we don't
know we don't know his name we don't
that little boy was a type of the very
work that Jesus was to do because Jesus
we know in the New Testament he what
does he call he's called the son of
David
David he was brought into this world
because of our sin and though he was
innocent and had done no wrong he died
that we might live and so you begin to
see these stories in the Bible that you
know you think yeah that that story
doesn't mean anything you just kind of
throw it to the side but God wastes
nothing so these stories in the
scriptures that we that we tend to read
and does kind of gloss over when we stop
and begin to think okay what's God
trying to show me here this Harv you the
Bible one of the examples I'd like to
give is this imagine we're in a
primitive society and a camera drops
right in the midsummer eyes over drops
the camera right in the midst of our
society and we're like what is that no
one wants to touch it we don't know what
it is we've never seen it before and
then after a few weeks and months
someone gets bold enough to go close to
it and touch it and okay doesn't do
anything it's not gonna hurt us and now
this is an object that we just you know
we just worship we do wow look at this
thing we set it up on our rock and
everyone comes to look at the camera
whoa look at the camera
this is an amazing thing let me ask you
is that primitive society using the
camera in the right way
mmm no what is the purpose of the camera
to take pictures to take pictures the
stories of the Bible are cameras hmm
that reveal the picture of Jesus Wow
most of us approach these stories and
just look at the camera oh what a neat
camera Wow that's a beautiful camera Hey
look at this camera yeah look at that
camera man these cameras are great not
realizing that these cameras were
designed to show us Jesus so in essence
we end up missing the picture picture
Wow
that's what ends up happening we often
read the Bible and miss the picture of
Jesus right you guys remember and this
is this is one of my strong beliefs when
it comes to photo theology photo
theology is the art of looking for Jesus
hmm it's the art of looking for Jesus so
on the road to Emmaus mm-hmm
you remember the disciples they were
heartbroken because Jesus had just died
right now Jesus comes to them but they
don't know that it's him their eyes are
holding so they can't recognize him and
he begins they begin telling him he's
like why so sad
they begin telling him all these reasons
why they are the sad discouraged and all
those things and then he he says to them
all fools and slow of heart to believe
all that the prophets have said should
not these things have been fulfilled and
in Bible says beginning from Moses and
the prophets he began to expound to them
in the scriptures all the things
concerning himself mm-hmm in other words
he's given these discouraged disciples a
Bible study they've just lost the guy
that they thought was the Messiah right
I don't know about you but you know
someone dies and you that's you're close
to you're probably not in the mood for
your you wanna just mourn Jesus decides
to pull them out of their mourning by
giving them a Bible study that Bible
study must have been so deep and
powerful because after it was done they
were like did not our hearts burn yeah
people heard me say before heartburn
yeah it's where Harper yes when because
Jesus began to show them himself in all
the scriptures so beginning at Moses and
the prophets he expounds unto them and
all the Scriptures the things concerning
himself that means that Jesus is on
every page Jesus is all over the Old
Testament it's like Waldo I just love
those Oh Where's Waldo books you know
that Waldo is in there somewhere yeah
right so when I read the scripture when
you read the scripture photo theology is
the art of looking for Jesus on every
page of the scriptures mm-hmm right
beginning from Moses and the prophets so
in Genesis 1 God said let there be light
ah whoa Jesus is light in Genesis 2 God
brings the water to you know what it
makes prominent the waters so Jesus is
the water of life on that's I'm sorry as
Genesis 1 on day 2 on day 3 the Bible
says that God brought the fruits from
the earth so on day 3 the first fruits
came forth from the ground on the third
day the first fruits you can read that
and just not connect the dots mm-hmm
because you're not
you've heard of seeing a picture is
worth God is into pictures just look at
the book of Revelation right it's all
about images yeah right the book of
daniel god is into pictures god is an
artist yes god is creative by nature and
so often we approach the scriptures with
this you know narrow there's what the
text says and we stop right there and
you know I mean it is it is it is a
challenge
when you approach the scriptures because
you that what the text says is
absolutely important okay but there's a
dimension beyond that right that is
beyond the ink on the paper right that
God has to bring it so it's like when
Jesus said except you eat my flesh and
drink my blood
the Jews were like what how dare you
yeah do you not know our our you know
Jewish customs what are you talking
about eating flesh and drinking blood
are you crazy
they could not understand the spiritual
significance of his words so they took
literally what he meant to be spiritual
or symbolic destroy this temple and in
three days I'll raise it up again
did you hear what this guy said he's
gonna destroy the temple we've been
building for 46 years
not realizing he was speaking about the
temple of his body right right so the
way that Jesus approached the scriptures
he approached it in a very creative
because he is the creator